<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>radare2 on A Blog.</title>
    <link>https://bananamafia.dev/tags/radare2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in radare2 on A Blog.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bananamafia.dev/tags/radare2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>pwntools-r2</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/project/pwntools-r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/project/pwntools-r2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>r2con 2019 CTF Writeups</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/r2ctf-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/r2ctf-2019/</guid>
      <description>r2boy1 The first GameBoy challenge was rather easy. The idea was to talk to the Pancake character in-game in order to get the flag. The problem is that Pancake chills behind a wall. One possible solution was to glitch through the wall, however I&amp;rsquo;ve solved this using static analysis.
Going through the strings and searching for a possible dialog yields interesting strings:
[0x00054075]&amp;gt; izzq~pancake 0x54016 37 36 Find pancake\nthrough a game\nglitch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROP On x64: What&#39;s ret2csu Again?</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/x64-rop-redpwn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/x64-rop-redpwn/</guid>
      <description>Based on the Stop, ROP, n&amp;rsquo;, Roll challenge from this year&amp;rsquo;s Redpwn CTF, this post will explain how to make system calls on x64 using ROP in order to spawn a shell. Also, it shows how to abuse writable memory regions of a process to overcome difficulties with some ROP gadgets. And the best thing is, two of the gadgets used in this writeup are universal and most likely also present in your x64 target if it&amp;rsquo;s using glibc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROP It Like It&#39;s Hot: ROP Basics - Stack Pivoting</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/binary-rop-stackpivot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/binary-rop-stackpivot/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s check out Return Oriented Programming (ROP) with the pivot32 challenge from ROP Emporium by using radare2. The pivot32 binary is compiled without stack canaries and PIE but has NX enabled.
Basics The general principle behind ROP is that:
[&amp;hellip;] an attacker gains control of the call stack to hijack program control flow and then executes carefully chosen machine instruction sequences that are already present in the machine&amp;rsquo;s memory, called &amp;ldquo;gadgets&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brute-Forcing x86 Stack Canaries</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/binary-canary-bruteforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/binary-canary-bruteforce/</guid>
      <description>And now for something more CTF-y: Dealing with stack canaries by brute-forcing their value byte by byte.
How Stack Canaries Work If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever read the error message *** stack smashing detected ***: &amp;lt;...&amp;gt; terminated, you&amp;rsquo;ve already encountered stack canaries in action. They are being used to detect and stop buffer overflows by placing a per-process randomized value between the local variables and the saved return address. If an attacker somehow manages to write across the boundary of a buffer in order to overwrite the saved return address, he will also overwrite the canary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>r2con 2019 PwnDebian Challenge: Exploiting radare2 (CVE-2019-14745)</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/r2-pwndebian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/r2-pwndebian/</guid>
      <description>Hello hello!
Everyone knows: This years r2con, the conference about radare2, has a very special challenge &amp;ndash; PwnDebian:
The almighty blenk92 and me decided to assist the radare2 project in finding such an exploit an we think we were quite successful :)
But first some basics for r2.
Shelling Out Via The r2 Shell While running r2, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to shell out and execute shell commands without leaving the r2 console:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buffer Overflows on x64 with radare2</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/x64-bof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/x64-bof/</guid>
      <description>The approach to exploit buffer overflows on x64 is a bit different that on x86. This post demonstrates this using the split challenge of ROP Emporium while making use of radare2.
RIP &amp;amp; Canonical Addresses The first thing one notices when trying to gain control over the instruction pointer is that only values of a specific range are allowed to be loaded into the RIP register. On x86 arbitrary values can be loaded into the instruction pointer register (EIP) - on x64 only canonical values are allowed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bypassing ASLR and DEP for 32-Bit Binaries With r2</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/binary-aslr-dep-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/binary-aslr-dep-32/</guid>
      <description>This post covers basic basics of bypassing ASLR and DEP with r2. For this, a vulnerable application, yolo.c, is required:
#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;stdlib.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;string.h&amp;gt; void lol(char *b) { char buffer[1337]; strcpy(buffer, b); } int main(int argc, char **argv) { lol(argv[1]); }  64-Bit vs 32-Bit Binaries The issue here should be quite obvious - strcpy blindly copies the user-controlled input buffer b into buffer which causes a buffer overflow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>