<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cve on BananaMafia</title>
    <link>https://bananamafia.dev/tags/cve/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cve on BananaMafia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bananamafia.dev/tags/cve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>r2con 2019 PwnDebian Challenge: Exploiting radare2 (CVE-2019-14745, CVE-2019-16718)</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/r2-pwndebian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/r2-pwndebian/</guid>
      <description>Hello hello!
Everyone knows: This years r2con, the conference about radare2, has a very special challenge &amp;ndash; PwnDebian:
The almighty blenk92 and me decided to assist the radare2 project in finding such an exploit an we think we were quite successful :)
But first some basics for r2.
Shelling Out Via The r2 Shell While running r2, it&#39;s possible to shell out and execute shell commands without leaving the r2 console:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Unqoted Service Paths For Fun and No Profit</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/realtek-driverutil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/realtek-driverutil/</guid>
      <description>This kind of vulnerability is really old. However, vendors still fail to properly address this issue. This is just another example of exploiting this kind of vulnerability on Windows 10 with the most up-to-date ALFA AWUS036AC driver utility (version 1030.6). Note that the download link points to alfa.com but the driver utility itself says it&#39;s developed by REALTEK.
The vulnerability Upon installing the driver utility, two vulnerable services get installed. This can be checked using the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auditing WriteDiary.com</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/write-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/write-diary/</guid>
      <description>WriteDiary consists of a webapp and an Android app (version 4.72). For the audit, the android app was the primary target.
The developer and owner of both the webapp and android app has been contacted multiple times to develop a quick fix for the issues addressed in this blog post and a vulnerability concerning the webapp which isn&#39;t described here. However, no response has been received. This is bad, as you will see in the first finding:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>