<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gamehacking on BananaMafia</title>
    <link>https://bananamafia.dev/tags/gamehacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gamehacking on BananaMafia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bananamafia.dev/tags/gamehacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Hacking #3: Hooking Direct3D EndScene()</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/d3dhook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/d3dhook/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with even moar game hacking and hooking techniques and you didn&amp;rsquo;t, so here comes another blog post.
Today&amp;rsquo;s topic is about hooking a specific function of the Direct 3D library with the goal to cause Counter Strike: Global Offensive to draw additional things on the screen. There can be various reasons to do this:
 It&amp;rsquo;s possible to draw a crosshair on the screen when none is shown by the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Hacking #2: Coding A CS:GO Hack</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/bananabot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/bananabot/</guid>
      <description>This post covers creating a hack for the game Counter Strike: Global Offensive. The hack I&amp;rsquo;ve developed works in combination with the Linux version of the game - coding a windows-based hack can however be done with the same methodology and tools.
These are the features I&amp;rsquo;ve integrated into the hack:
 Bunnyhop Bot: Do jumps as soon as the player hits the ground to make it easier to perform bunny hop chains No Flash: Be immune to flash grenades that would block the players vision Aimbot: Automatically aim at the head of the nearest enemy  Tooling &amp;amp; Setup Linux lacks of good tools to perform the kind of analysis tasks required to code a cheat like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Hacking #1: Developing Hacks for idTech3 Based Games</title>
      <link>https://bananamafia.dev/post/multihack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bananamafia.dev/post/multihack/</guid>
      <description>The idTech3 game engine is most known for being used in games like Quake III Arena, Wolfenstein: ET and Star Wars: Jedi Knight - Jedi Academy. Sometimes people just simply refer to this engine as the Quake3 engine. This post teaches you how to create hacks for games that are based on this game engine. The target of choice is the game Jedi Academy, which was released in 2003. Oldschool, I know - but most of the injection and hooking techniques can also be applied to modern games.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>